<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on moomou</title>
    <link>https://moomou.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on moomou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/moomou&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 23:01:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moomou.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ML paper notes</title>
      <link>https://moomou.github.io/notes/ml_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 23:01:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moomou.github.io/notes/ml_notes/</guid>
      <description>2017-09 DISTILLING THE KNOWLEDGE IN A NEURAL NETWORK  explores compression technique of ensemble model into a single model Distillation  softmax qi = exp(zi/T)/Sigma(j)(exp(zj/T) where z are logits and T is temperature  T is usually 1 increasing T creates softer probability distribution  knowledge is tranferred via training smaller/compressed model by targeting over softer target (ie temperature T &amp;gt; 1) from more cumbersome model small model trained with higher T as well but in prediction mode uses T = 1 tranfer training can be improved by using datasets with true label  demonstrate distillation with minist dataset - tranfer works well even when smaller model trained by omitting certain numbers discusses using soft distribution target technique for training specialists on very large datasets Google internal JFT data of 100M images  Questions  teacher - student model, relation to curriculum learning?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://moomou.github.io/notes/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 23:01:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moomou.github.io/notes/tools/</guid>
      <description>Fzf Amazing command line tool to fuzzy search for files. Cannot live without this. Also integrates with vim.
https://github.com/junegunn/fzf
Jq Swiss army knife for working with JSON on the command line
https://github.com/stedolan/jq
Pup Like Jq, but for HTML
https://github.com/ericchiang/pup
Silversearcher Like grep, but better
https://github.com/ggreer/the_silver_searcher</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>