<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on moomou</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on moomou</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>since 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating within a Mono Repo</title>
      <link>/posts/2024-06-01-gd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2024-06-01-gd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;groot-and-friends&#34;&gt;Groot and Friends&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigating within a mono repo can be tedious.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I frequently find myself doing &lt;code&gt;cd ../..&lt;/code&gt; to navigate to sibling folders or jumping to the root of the git directory to navigate and inspect other part of the code base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To navigate to the root of the Git repository, I use an alias &lt;code&gt;groot&lt;/code&gt; defined as&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    alias groot=&amp;#39;cd $(git rev-parse --show-toplevel)&amp;#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excellent tools such as &lt;code&gt;fd&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt; help a lot but I want to be able to jump to different part of the repo with a few keystrokes. For example, in a mono repo, I want to be quickly jump from go/src/mou.dev/cmd to schema/proto.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening with LLM</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-12-31-listening-with-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023-12-31-listening-with-llm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first part of many posts I am writing to consolidate learnings on how to finetune Large Language Models (LLMs) to process audio, with the eventual goal of being able to build and host a LLM able to describe human voices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am motivated to gain hands-on experience tinkering LLMs so, as much as practical, I tried to recreate utilities and functions with pytorch from scratch rather than rely on 3rd party libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Debug Gibberish</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-12-27-ohmy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023-12-27-ohmy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I went down a rabbit hole of debugging opensource LLM spewing gibberish on my PC.&#xA;The investigation was the one of the most difficult (but interesting) debugging experience I have encountered so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog will chronicle the problem I encountered, debugging steps I took, and finally, the resolution and workaround I adopted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt; I traced down the source of LLM spewing gibberish to faulty RAM sticks after getting different sha256 checksums on a static file on different runs. I was then able to salvage ~40% of the faulty RAM stick capacity after discovering Linux kernl parameter &lt;code&gt;memtest=&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CORS with Cookie</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-08-13-cors-with-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2022-08-13-cors-with-cookie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CORS stands for Cross-Origin-Resource-Sharing and is the HTTP mechanism to&#xA;allow servers to accept requests from other host locations other than its own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting CORS up and running is not difficult. There are plenty of posts online that will&#xA;recommend a starting configuration that looks something like this, in pseudo code&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Header().Set(&amp;quot;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;)&#xA;Header().Set(&amp;quot;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;POST, GET, OPTIONS, PUT, DELETE&amp;quot;)&#xA;Header().Set(&amp;quot;Access-Control-Allow-Headers&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Accept, Content-Type, Content-Length, Authorization&amp;quot;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This configuration works great and is the default I use; however, it does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; work if you need to receive and set cookies in the browser. This short blog post documents what I learnt&#xA;about working with cookies with CORS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messing with Nvidia GPU on Headless Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-29-nvidia-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-29-nvidia-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a PC with Ubuntu server installed and Nvidia GPUs attached. I have Googled on and off for a while trying to learn how to overclock the GPUs without success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, after gleaning bits and parts from different sources, I got power limit and overclocking working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps required&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-monitor&#34;&gt;Virtual Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nvidia-settings&lt;/code&gt; need a monitor attached in order to work. For headless linux, one needs a virtual monitor. After messing with xorg conf manually for a while, I found and forked &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andyljones/coolgpus&#34;&gt;andyljones/coolgpus&lt;/a&gt; to automatically attach a virtual monitor for each GPU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvements to &#34;m&#34;, a personal command line tool</title>
      <link>/posts/dev-ux2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dev-ux2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-m-to-m2&#34;&gt;From m to m2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having used &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; for many years now, I encountered two primary problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first is startup performance. Even with lazy module loading (see &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/dev-ux&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), calling &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; without any subcommands still took ~250ms on my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second problem is code verbosity. To add a new command, one needs to create a new class in a separate file, import it in main, and finally instantiate the new class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Speaker Embedding from Scratch with Triplet Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/speaker-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 23:01:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/speaker-embedding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Posted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.mou.dev/triplet-embedding-learning&#34;&gt;go.mou.dev/triplet-embedding-learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Experience</title>
      <link>/posts/dev-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 23:01:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dev-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;commandline-productivity-and-automation-aka-make-it-easy-to-repeat&#34;&gt;Commandline Productivity and Automation (aka make it easy to repeat)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developers tend to repeat themselves. A lot. This can be as innocuous as running a test manually after you update a test file or as insidious as deploying a newly built binary into production manually. Nobody likes to repeat themselves over and over again. And for good reasons. Not only does it take time to repeatedly figure out all the parameters in a tricky command line program, it also increases stress when you are trying to fix outages as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
